# PRADIP GADAL

Ph. No: +9779825381265, Email: Pradip.gadal.369@gmail.com, Address: Biratnagar, Koshi Province, Nepal

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Organized Professional Teacher with 5+ years of experience in teaching foundations of Physics, Science and Mathematics. Skilled in identifying the core problem areas of the students and providing clear explanations to better grasp difficult topics. Highly adaptable to unpredictable school settings and keen on discussing ways to improve the student's learning experience with the staff and school administration.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

<u>Tuition Teacher</u> (Feb 2016 – Jul 2018)

D.A.V School, Biratnagar, Koshi Province Nepal

Website: <a href="https://www.dav.edu.np/">https://www.dav.edu.np/</a>

 Responsible for assisting in the complete education and social development of pupils as a tuition teacher. In charge of organizing classes and responding to the strengths and needs of students during lessons.

# **Secondary Mathematics Teacher**

(Jun 2018 - Oct 2020)

Galaxy Public High School, Biratnagar, Koshi Province, Nepal

Website: <a href="https://galaxy.edu.np/">https://galaxy.edu.np/</a>

- Implemented the designated curriculum completely and daily lesson plan as well.
- Researched based on day plan
- provided opportunities for students to access and use current technology, resources and information to solve problems.
- Provided personal tuition according to child behaviors
- Helped students develop problem-solving skills and mathematical thinking
- Assigned reasonable assignments to students as per school rules
- Helped improve curriculum as well as social skills.

## **Secondary Mathematics Teacher**

(May 2021 – Jun 2023)

**Balmeeki Memorial Boarding Secondary School**, Pathari Sanishchare-2, Koshi Province, Nepal Website: https://www.facebook.com/balmeeki/

- Trained for preparing national-level mathematics question
- Presented the subject using slides and a smart board.
- Helped students for science and mathematics exhibition
- Created curriculum design and daily lesson plane
- Created a safe learning environment for student

### ADDITIONAL SKILL

## **Personal Skill**

• Time management, Hardworking, Building Trust, Adaptability and Active Listening, Strong Determination, enjoy working with people.

## **Professional Skill**

 Trained with different programs related to question making, course breakdown, curriculum and different teaching methodologies, Tech-friendly, Understanding Child behaviours, Developing and continuous improvement in teaching, educational and recreational processes, and Knowledge of related administrative and clerical procedures.

# **Digital Skill**

- Soft Skill: Social Media, Zoom, Google Drive, Dropbox, Microsoft Office, PowerPoint, etc.
- Tech Skills: JavaScript, Python, React, SQL, Version Control, Cinema 3D.

# Language Skill

• Nepal (Native), English (fluent), Hindi (fluent)

## EDUCATION AND TRAINING

## MASTER IN SCIENCE WITH MAJOR PHYSICS

(13/02/2013 - Running)

Tribhuvan University, Biratnagar, Koshi Province, Nepal

Website: https://tu.edu.np/

Field of study: Physics Final grade: Running

## BACHELOR IN SCIENCE WITH MAJOR PHYSICS

(13/02/2017 - 11/12/2021)

Tribhuvan University, Biratnagar, Koshi Province, Nepal

Website: https://tu.edu.np/

Field of study: Physic, Mathematics, Chemistry and Computer Final grade: 60%

## NATIONAL EXAMINATIONS BOARD(NEB)

(15/06/2014 - 19/7/2016)

**Orchid College**, Biratnagar, Koshi Province, Nepal **Website:** http://www.orchidcollege.edu.np/

Field of study: Science, Mathematics and Computer Final grade: 66.70%

#### SCHOOL LEAVING CERTIFICATE EXAMINATION (SLC)

(6/03/2001 - 17/02/2014)

Araniko Memorial Secondary English School-AMES, Amardaha, Koshi Province, Nepal

**Website:** https://www.facebook.com/ames2052/

Field of study: Opt. Mathematics Final grade: 80%

#### PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

Secondary Level Mathematics Teacher - 2021 Jan

Galaxy Public High School, Biratnagar-12

Secondary Level Mathematics Teacher - 2023 Jun

Balmeeki Memorial Boarding Secondary School, Pathari -2